# ENGR. IRSHAD AHMED

SOFTWARE ENGINEER | FULL STACK DEVELOPER

## **PROFILE**

I am passionate Software Engineer my core expertise are at HTML, CSS, Bootstrap, JavaScript, Core PHP, Laravel, CI, AWS-MySQL, MYSQL Database, and Umbraco .NET Framework. Always at forefront to grasp the concept and overview of modern technologies. As a Software Engineer. I have worked on different kinds of things such as Desktop apps ,Web Apps , Android Apps. I am working as full stack web developer at various freelancing platforms. I have worked on different kinds of projects such as Desktop apps ,Web Apps , and Android Apps.

# CONTACT

- +92 308 262 2931
- irshadsoomro.08@gmail.com
- ( irshadsoomro.github.io
- House No 610/1, 4th floor flat No 108 PECHS block #02 Comm Area Tariq Road Karachi.

#### EDUCATION

## **MS Artificial Intelligence**

NED University Karachi | 2021 - 2022

## **BE Software Engineering**

Mehran University Jamshoro | 2016 - 2020

#### **HSC Pre Engineering**

C&S Degree College Shikarpur | 2014 - 2016

## **CERTIFICATION**

#### Machine Learning & Data Science

IBA University Sukkur | 2019 - 2019

### **Custom Website Development**

Udemy Course | 2018 - 2018

# PORTFOLIO =



Or Click Here

## WORK EXPERIENCE

#### **Full Stack Developer**

HBOX Digital | 2021 - Present

I am leading developers team, managing projects and bidding on projects. Here I am following Agile Software Development life cycle. I developed here lot of websites using (HTML, CSS, Bootstrap, JavaScript, jQuery, PHP, MySQL, AWS MySQL, and Umbraco .NET) Developed Website Alpha Coupons Lab, Guild Wood Construction, At Your Door Labs (Website, Landing Page, CMS), Allee Construction, LeapX, Paramount Textile Group and lot of other landing pages and website.

#### Website Designer & Developer

OBHOST LLC | 2020 - 2021

OBHOST is a hosting, domain, and VPS server provider agency. My task was maintain there websites and develop new websites for clients. I worked on WHMCS APIs, Crypto APIs, HTML, CSS, JS, Bootstrap, JSON, PHP, and MySQL. Here I developed lot of websites Crypto Profit Calculator, Hostingwalay [Website, Lead Generating Landing Pages (Unlimited Hosting Mega Sale, PK Unlimited, VPS Server), CMS], Domainwalay, SSL. VOIP Solution and lot of other webiste for clients.

#### Software Engineer

Freelance Work | 2019 - Present

I am working here as teacher, developer, designer, and writer. I developed lot of website for local/online clients (Online Wakeel, EasyPlay, ECA-Rightmove, The DEN Lion of Affrica, Roulette Syllabus, Jamia Darulluloom Sukkur, the-bettercart and lot of other website). Also I teach web developement, How to create PowerPoint Presentation, Video Editing, and Graphics Designing.

#### SKILLS

HTML, CSS, SASS	Graphic Design, SEO, SMM
Umbraco .NET	Bootstrap
JavaScript	C++, Java, Python
Core PHP	Laravel, CI
WHMCS APIS	MySQL, AWS MySQL